Modern cities host huge events every week - cricket, concerts, rallies.
But traffic control is still reactive: we respond only after the jam forms.
TraffiSense.ai changes that: a predictive, simulation-driven command platform.
Built on 8,000+ real Bengaluru ASTraM incidents, with MapMyIndia mapping.
Planning starts with an event.
Pick a real venue - M. Chinnaswamy Stadium - 40,000 attendance, 7 PM Saturday, clear weather.
One click predicts impact, simulates strategies, optimizes resources, and plans emergency routes.
Here's the forecast: predicted congestion blooms across the CBD corridors.
A gravity demand model fuses event load, historical incident density, and an ML closure-risk score.
Every corridor is explained: 1,300 vehicles, 61% saturation, 19 min delay, 40% closure risk.
Resource deployment - officers, barricades, marshals, tow trucks - allocated by marginal need.
Mekhri Circle, a chronic hotspot with 64 incidents, gets the most officers: ~19% queue reduction.
Every recommendation ships with a plain-English rationale.
Divert, retime signals, or both?
The scenario engine compares five strategies: travel time, queue, emergency response, emissions.
Full optimization delivers a 30% cut in average travel time - a digital twin to test plans safely.
Just ask. The command assistant answers natural-language what-ifs, live from the simulation.
What happens if heavy rain begins?
Worst corridor 61% to 100%, severe corridors 0 to 7, delay 15 to 59 min. Pre-position tow trucks.
Under the hood: real machine learning.
A RandomForest predicts road closures - an imbalanced 7% problem - with data leakage caught and removed.
Honest holdout AUC 0.80, a 4.3x lift over the base rate, and stable 5-fold cross-validation.
TraffiSense.ai - anticipate, test every plan, deploy with confidence. Proactive, at last.